Guide to the Belmont Family Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Belmont Family Papers
1799-1930.
Belmont family.
27 linear ft (ca. 13,000 items in 64 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079136
History
August Belmont (1813-1890) was a banker, politician, and American agent of the Rothschilds; his son August Belmont (1853-1924) was a financier and sportsman.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, copies of letters, documents, manuscripts, invitations, menus, clippings, school papers, leases, agreements, deeds, financial accounts, photographs, and printed miscellany. The papers deal with many aspects of the Belmont family interests from 1799 until 1930, including: finance, banking and the Rothschilds; the United States Navy, Commodore Matthew C. Perry (1794-1858) and the Perry expeditions to Mexico and Japan; Belmont's embassy to The Netherlands from 1853 to 1857; the Democratic Party, New York City politics, presidential and Civil War politics; social life in New York and Newport and European travel; horses, horse breeding, The Jockey Club, polo, the Remount Association (for cavalry horses in World War I), fox hunting, dog breeding, and yachting; New York subway construction, railroads, the Cape Cod Canal and aviation; the Democratic Convention of 1912; and genealogical notes on the Belmont, Perry, and other families. In addition to the correspondence, there are 117 letter books, tissue-paper copies of outgoing letters.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged. The collection is arranged into three series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Uncataloged Papers
Series III: Letterbooks
Subjects
Jockey Club (New York, N.Y.); Remount Association.; Democratic Party (U.S.); United States Naval Expedition to Japan (1852-1854); Belmont, August, 1813-1890.; Belmont, August, 1853-1924.; Perry, Matthew Calbraith, 1794-1858.; Cape Cod Canal (Mass.); New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; Rhode Island--Genealogy.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Newport (R.I.)--Social life and customs.; Europe--Description and travel.; Real property--United States.; Banks and banking--United States.; Finance--United States.; Presidents--United States--Election.; Horses--United States.; Horse racing--United States--Societies, etc.; World War, 1914-1918--Horses.; Fox hunting--United States.; Yachts--United States.; Dogs--Breeding--United States.; Cavalry--United States--Remounts.; Remount service.; Subways--New York (State)--New York.; Underground construction.; Railroads--United States.; Canals--Massachusetts.; Aeronautics.; Political conventions.; Deeds.; Genealogies.; Leases.; Letterpress copybooks.; Menus.; Photoprints.; Bank presidents.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
The following boxes are located on-site: C1-C13.
The following boxes are located off-site: 1-51. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
06/--/82 M82-06 Belmont, August, IV Gift
Gift of August Belmont, IV, 1982.
Selected Related Material-- at Columbia
Eleanor Robson Belmont Papers, Barnard College Archives.
Contents list, 11p.
Finding aid in repository and online.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Adams, Charles Francis, 1807-1886 (Box C1)
  - Adams, Charles Francis, 1835-1915 (Box C1)
  - Adams, John Quincy, Jr. (Box C1)
  - Aiken, Frederick A. (Box C1)
  - Alexander, Charles Beatty, 1849-1927 (Box C1)
  - Alexander, Edward Porter, 1835-1910 (Box C1)
  - Allen, Frederick Hobbes,-1937 (Box C1)
  - Ames, Winthrop, 1871-1937 (Box C1)
  - Anderson, Henry James, 1799-1875 (Box C1)
  - Appleton, Daniel, 1852-1929 (Box C1)
  - Appleton, Francis Randall, 1854-1929 (Box C1)
  - Appleton, William Henry, 1814-1899 (Box C1)
  - Arenberg, (Prince) August e-Louis-Alberic von, 1837-1924 (Box C1)
  - Arkell, William J., 1856-1930 (Box C1)
  - Arthur, Chester Alan, 1830-1886 (Box C1)
  - Astor, Charlotte August a Gibbs (Mrs. John Jacob),-1887 (Box C1)
  - Auerbach, Joseph Smith,-1944 (Box C1)
  - Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937 (Box C1)
  - Bakhmetev, Iurii,-1928 (Box C1)
  - Barlow, Samuel Lathan Mitchell, 1826-1889 (Box C1)
  - Barlow, Larocque & MacFarland (Box C1)
  - Barreda, F. L. (Box C1)
  - Barreda, Matilde L. (Box C1)
  - Barrett, John, 1866-1938 (Box C1)
  - Bartholdi, Frédéric August e, 1834-1904 (Box C1)
  - Bartlett, Franklin, 1847-1909 (Box C1)
  - Battersea, Cyril Flower, Baron, 1843-1907 (Box C1)
  - Bayard, Thomas Francis, 1828-1898 (Box C1)
  - Beaufort, Henry Charles FitzRoy Somerset, 8th Duke of, 1824-1899 (Box C1)
  - Bell, Henry (Box C1)
  - Bell, Edward R. (Box C1)
  - Bell, Isaac, 1846-1889 (Box C1)
  - Bell, (Sir) Isaac Lowthian, 1816-1904 (Box C1)
  - Bell, Lilie (Box C1)
  - Belmont, Alice de Goicouria, 1910- (Box C1)
  - Belmont, Alice Wall de Goicouria (Mrs August ) (Box C1)
  - Belmont, Alva Ertskin Smith Vanderbilt (Mrs Oliver H.P.), 1853-1933 (Box C1)
  - Belmont, August, 1813-1890 (Box C2)
    (Arranged alphabetically by recipient)
  - Belmont, August, 1853-1924 (Box C3)
  - Belmont, August, 1882-1919 (Box C3)
  - Belmont, August, & Co. (Box C3)
  - Belmont, Bessie Morgan, 1907- (Box C3)
  - Belmont, Caroline Slidell Mackenzie Perry (Mrs. August ), 1829-1892 (Box C3)
  - Belmont, Carolyn Bowne Hulbert (Mrs. Raymond) (Box C3)
  - Belmont, Eleanor Robson (Mrs. August ), 1879-1979 (Box C3)
  - Belmont, Elizabeth Hamilton Morgan (Mrs. August ), 1862-1898 (Box C3)
  - Belmont, Jane Pauline, 1856-1875 (Box C4)
  - Belmont, Morgan, 1892- (Box C4)
  - Belmont, Oliver Hazard Perry, 1858-1908 (Box C4)
  - Belmont, Perry, 1850-1947 (Box C4)
  - Belmont, Raymond, 1888- (Box C4)
  - Belmont, Raymond Rodgers, 1863-1887 (& cataloged manuscripts) (Box C4)
  - Bennett, James Gordon, 1841-1918 (Box C4)
  - Berdan, Hiram (Box C4)
  - Berendt, Joanna Feist (Mrs. Martin) (Box C4)
  - Beresford, (Lord) Marcus Talbot De la Poer, 1848-1922 (Box C4)
  - Betti, Francois (Box C4)
  - Bigelow, Henry Forbes, 1867-1929 (Box C4)
  - Bigelow, Henry Nelson (Box C4)
  - Bingham, Harry, 1821-1900 (Box C4)
  - Bishop, Courtlandt Field (Box C4)
  - Blair, Frank Preston, 1821-1875 (Box C4)
  - Blair, Henry William, 1834-1920 (Box C4)
  - Bleichröder, Gerson, Baron von, 1822-1893 (Box C4)
  - Bliss, Cornelius Newton, 1874-1949 (Box C4)
  - Bliss, Robert Woods, 1875-, & Mildred Barnei Bliss (Box C4)
  - Bogy, Lewis Vital, 1813-1877 (Box C5)
  - Bonheur, Rosa, 1822-1899 (Box C5)
  - Borglum, Gutzon, 1871-1941 (Box C5)
  - Boutwell, George Sewall, l8l8-1905 (Box C5)
  - Bowen, John Templeton, 1857-1940 (Box C5)
  - Bowers, Arthur F. (Box C5)
  - Brach, Frederika Feist (Mrs. Rudolf), 1843- (Box C5)
  - Brooks, James Wilton, 1854-1916 (Box C5)
  - Brown, Henry Collins, 1863- (Box C5)
  - Brown, Stewart (Box C5)
  - Brugsch, Heinrich Karl, 1827-1894 (Box C5)
  - Buchanan, James, 1791-1868 (Box C5)
  - Bull, William Lanman, 1844-1914 (Box C5)
  - Bullard, Robert Lee, 1861-1947 (Box C5)
  - Burgess, Edward, 1848-1891 (Box C5)
  - Burnett, Harry (Box C5)
  - Burnett, Joseph, 1820-1894 (Box C5)
  - Butler, Matthew Calbraith, 1836-1909 (Box C5)
  - Butler, Matthew Calbraith [Jr.] (Box C5)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947 (Box C5)
  - Butterfield, Daniel, 1831-1901 (Box C5)
  - Cadwalader, John Lambert, 1837-1914 (Box C5)
  - Calvet, J. (Box C5)
  - Carroll, Charles (Box C5)
  - Carroll, John Lee, 1830-1911 (Box C5)
  - Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866 (Box C5)
  - Cassel, (Sir) Ernest Joseph, 1852-1921 (Box C5)
  - Chambers, David Laurance, 1879- (Box C5)
  - Chappell, Absalom Harris, 1801-I878 (Box C5)
  - Chase, Salmon Portland, 1808-1873 (Box C5)
  - Chase, Theodore (Box C5)
  - Chase, Thomas, 1827-1892 (Box C5)
  - Chester, Colby Mitchell, 1844-1932 (Box C5)
  - Child, Francis James, 1825-1896 (Box C5)
  - Church, George Hervey, 1855-1935 (Box C5)
  - Church, Sanford E. (Box C5)
  - Clanton, James H. (Box C5)
  - Clarke, Joseph Ignatius Constantine, 1846-1925 (Box C5)
  - Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908 (Box C5)
  - Coggeshall, Thomas (Box C6)
  - Coit, Henry August us, 1830-1895 (Box C6)
  - Coleman, Charles Caryl, 1840-1928 (Box C6)
  - Collier, Peter Fenelon, 1849-1909 (Box C6)
  - Comeau, L. de (Box C6)
  - Conkling, Alfred Ronald, 1850 (Box C6)
  - Connery, Thomas B. (Box C6)
  - Converse, G. S. (Box C6)
  - Converse, William M. (Box C6)
  - Cooley, James S. (Box C6)
  - Coon, Charles E. (Box C6)
  - Cooper, Edward, 1824-1905 (Box C6)
  - Corbin, Amy Foster (Mrs. John) (Box C6)
  - Corbin, Austin, 1827-1896 (Box C6)
  - Corbin, John, 1870-1959 (Box C6)
  - Cornwallis, Kinahan, 1839-1917 (Box C6)
  - Coudert, Frederic Rene, 1832-1903 (Box C6)
  - Cox, Samuel Sullivan, 1824-1889 (Box C6)
  - Cravath, Paul Drennan, 1861-1940 (Box C6)
  - Crawford, Samuel Wylie, 1829-1892 (Box C6)
  - Creighton, W. (Box C6)
  - Crosby, John Schuyler, 1839-1914 (Box C6)
  - Crowninshield, Frank, 1872-1947 (Box C6)
  - Cummings, Prentiss (Box C6)
  - Cunard, (Sir) Bache Edward, 1851-1925 (Box C6)
  - Cunliffe-Owen, Frederick,-1926 (Box C6)
  - Cutting, William (Box C6)
  - Dana, Paul, 1852-1930 (Box C6)
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948 (Box C6)
  - Davies, Joseph Edward, 1876-1958 (Box C6)
  - Davies, Julian Tappan, 1845-1920 (Box C6)
  - Davis, John William, 1873-1955 (Box C6)
  - Davis, Thomas E. (Box C6)
  - Dawes, Charles Gates, 1865-1951 (Box C6)
  - Day, Joseph Paul, 1873-1944 (Box C6)
  - Delafield, Richard, 1853-1930 (Box C6)
  - Delano, Warren (Box C6)
  - Delano, William Adams, 1874-1960 (Box C6)
  - Dempsey, Stephen Wallace, 1862-1949 (Box C6)
  - Denison, Charles, 18l8-l867 & George Washington Woodward, 1809-1875 (Box C6)
  - Derby, (Sir) Edward George Villiers, Stanley, 17 Earl of, 1865-1948 (Box C6)
  - Derby, Ethel Carow Roosevelt (Mrs. Richard) (Box C6)
  - D'Erlanger, (Baron) Emile Beaumont, 1866-1939 (Box C6)
  - De Saulles, Catherine Heckscher (Mrs. Arthur B.) (Box C6)
  - Dickinson, Jacob McGavock, 1851-1928 (Box C6)
  - Dillon, Robert James (Box C6)
  - Dix, John Alden, 1860-1928 (Box C6)
  - Donald, E. Winchester (Box C6)
  - Douglas, Stephen Arnold, l8l3-l86l (Box C6)
  - Dubois, Fred Thomas, 1851-1930 (Box C6)
  - Dufferin and Ava, Frederick Temple Hamilton-Temple-Blackwood, 1st Marquess of, 1826-1902 (Box C6)
  - Dunfermline, (Lady) Mary Elizabeth Elliot Abercromby, Baroness, 1811-l874 (Box C6)
  - Dunfermline, Ralph Abercromby, 2nd Baron, l803-1868 (Box C6)
  - Dunn, Joseph Allan Elphinstone, 1873-1941 (Box C6)
  - Eaton, Isaac E. (Box C6)
  - Eaton, William Wallace, 1816-1898 (Box C6)
  - Eckert, Thomas Thompson, 1825-1910 (Box C6)
  - Edward VIII, King of Great Britain, 1894-1973 (Box C6)
  - Eldridge, Frederick G. (Box C6)
  - Elias, Edward (Box C6)
  - Eliot, Walter Graeme, 1857- (Box C6)
  - Elssler, Fanny, 1810-1884 (Box C6)
  - Emmet, Emily Hone (Mrs. William C.) (Box C6)
  - Erlanger, (Baron) Frédéric Emile d' (Box C6)
  - Erlanger, Mathilde Slidell (Baroness Frédéric d’) (Box C6)
  - Everest, Charles W. (Box C6)
  - Fabbré, E. P. (Box C6)
  - Fairchild, Charles Stebbins, 1842-1924 (Box C6)
  - Farragut, David Glasgow, 1801-1870 (Box C6)
  - Feist, August, 1845- (Box C7)
  - Feist, Elizabeth Belmont (Mrs. Stephan, 1819-1876) (Box C7)
  - Feist, Stephan (Box C7)
  - Feist-Belmont, Carl, l844-1896 (Box C7)
  - Field, Cyrus West, 1819-1892 (Box C7)
  - Field, Marshall, II (Box C7)
  - Field, William B. Osgood & Otto Hermann Kahn, 1867-1934 (Box C7)
  - Finch, Daniel O. (Box C7)
  - Fish, Frederick Perry, 1855-1930 (Box C7)
  - Fish, Hamilton, 1808-1893 (Box C7)
  - Fish, Stuyvesant, 1851-1923 (Box C7)
  - Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947 (Box C7)
  - Fiske, Bradley Allen, 1854-1942 (Box C7)
  - Flexner, Anne Laziere Crawford (Mrs. Abraham) (Box C7)
  - Foss, Eugene Noble, 1858-1939 (Box C7)
  - Foster, Emily (Box C7)
  - Frederik, Prince of the Netherlands, 1797-1881 (Box C7)
  - Freedman, Andrew, 1860-1915 (Box C7)
  - French, Amos Tuck, 1863-1941 (Box C7)
  - Galbraith, William A. (Box C7)
  - Gallatin, Harriet Duer Robinson (Mrs. Albert), 1828-1893 (Box C7)
  - Ganay, Jean, Marquis de (Box C7)
  - Gardiner, Asa Bird, 1839-1919 (Box C7)
  - Gary, Elbert Henry, 1846-1927 (Box C7)
  - Gatliff, William (Box C7)
  - Gilmore, Alfred, 1812-1890 (Box C7)
  - Gerard, James Watson, 1867-1951 (Box C7)
  - Gore, Thomas Pryor, 1870-1949 (Box C7)
  - Gorman, Arthur Pue, 1839-1906 (Box C7)
  - Gottheil, Richard James Horatio, 1862-1936 (Box C7)
  - Grant, Hugh John, 1833- (Box C7)
  - Grant, Percy Stickney, 1860-1927 (Box C7)
  - Gray, George (Box C7)
  - Gray, John Clinton, 1843-1915 (Box C7)
  - Grayson, Cary Travers, 1878-1938 (Box C7)
  - Green, Charles Montraville, 1850-1928 (Box C7)
  - Green, John Pugh, 1839-1924 (Box C7)
  - Greenough, John, 1846-1934 (Box C7)
  - Greer, David Hummell, 1844-1919 (Box C7)
  - Greey, Edward, 1835-1888 (Box C7)
  - Griffin, Francis (Box C7)
  - Griswold, Frank Gray, 1854-l937 (Box C7)
  - Grosvenor, William Mercer, 1863-1916 (Box C7)
  - Guggenheim, Isaac, 1854-1922 (Box C7)
  - Gurney, Ephraim Whitman, 1829-1886 (Box C7)
  - Haggin, James B., 1827-1914 (Box C7)
  - Haldeman, Richard Jacobs, 1831-1886 (Box C7)
  - Halkett, Hugh Colin Gustave George Halkett, 3rd Baron, 1861-1904 (Box C7)
  - Hall, Abraham Oakey, 1826-1898 (Box C7)
  - Hancock, John, 1824-1893 (Box C7)
  - Hancock, Winfield Scott, l824-l886 (Box C7)
  - Handlett, Edward E. (Box C7)
  - Hanes, Lewis (Box C7)
  - Harding, Warren Gamaliel, 1865-1923 (Box C7)
  - Harding, William Proctor Gould, 1864-1930 (Box C7)
  - Harriman, Edward Henry, 1848-1909 (Box C7)
  - Harriman, Mary W. Averell (Mrs. Edward Henry) (Box C7)
  - Harriman, William Averell, 1891- (Box C7)
  - Hastings, Helen R. Benedict (Mrs. Thomas) (Box C7)
  - Hastings, Thomas, 1860-1929 (Box C7)
  - Hatch, Samuel Grantham, 1865-1918 (Box C7)
  - Hay, John, 1838-1905 (Box C7)
  - Heck, C. Louis (Box C7)
  - Hazard, Rowland Robinson (Box C7)
  - Heinrich, Frederic (Box C7)
  - Hendricks, Thomas Andrew, 1819-1885 (Box C7)
  - Herrick, Myron T., 1854-1929 (Box C7)
  - Hewitt, Eleanor G. (Box C7)
  - Hewitt, Sarah Cooper (Box C7)
  - Higginson, Henry Lee, 1834-1919 (Box C7)
  - Hill, Benjamin Harvey, 1823-1882 (Box C7)
  - Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949 (Box C7)
  - Hoey, Frederick (Box C8)
  - Hogan, Thomas (Box C8)
  - Hone, John [Sr.] (Box C8)
  - Hone, John (Box C8)
  - Hone, Josephine Hoey (Mrs. Charles Russell) (Box C8)
  - Hone, Robert G. (Box C8)
  - Howland, Frederika Elsass Belmont (Mrs. Samuel Shaw), 1854-1902 (Box C8)
  - Howland, Samuel Shaw (Box C8)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955 (Box C8)
  - Hunt, Richard Morris, 1827-1895 (Box C8)
  - Hunter, John (Box C8)
  - Huntington, William Reed, 1838- (Box C8)
  - Hurlbert, William Henry, 1827-1895 (Box C8)
  - Iselin, Charles Oliver,-1932 (Box C8)
  - Ives, Brayton, 1840-1914 (Box C8)
  - James, Cassie Mason Myers (Mrs. Julian) (Box C8)
  - James, Thomas Lemuel, 1831-1916 (Box C8)
  - Jay, Peter August us, 1877-1933 (Box C8)
  - Jerome, Leonard Walter, 1817-1891 (Box C8)
  - Jewett, Hugh Judge, 1817-1898 (Box C8)
  - Johnson, Herschel Vespasian, 1812-1880 (Box C8)
  - Johnson, Reverdy, 1796-1876 (Box C8)
  - Jones, George, 1800-1870 (Box C8)
  - Jones, George, 1811-1891 (Box C8)
  - Jones, Mary Cadwalader Rawle (Mrs. Frederic R.), 1850-1935 (Box C8)
  - Jones, Thomas Goode, 1844-1914 (Box C8)
  - Jourdan, James H.,-1938 (Box C8)
  - Judich, George A. (Box C8)
  - Kean, John, 1852-1914 (Box C8)
  - Kemble, William H. (Box C8)
  - Keppel, Frederick Paul, 1875-1943 (Box C8)
  - Kerr, Michael Crawford, 1827-1876 (Box C8)
  - Kerr, Walter Craig, 1858-1910 (Box C8)
  - King, William Henry, 1863-1949 (Box C8)
  - Krech, Alvin William, 1858-1928 (Box C8)
  - La Farge, Christopher Grant, 1862-1938 (Box C8)
  - La Farge, John, 1835-1910 (Box C8)
  - Lamont, Daniel Scott, 1851-1905 (Box C8)
  - Lamont, Thomas William, 1870-1948 (Box C8)
  - La Rochefoucauld, Emily Victorine Elizabeth Rumbold Cavindish (Countess Gaston de), 1824-1904 (Box C8)
  - Lawrence, William, 1850-1941 (Box C8)
  - Lazarus, Moses (Box C8)
  - Leavitt, Charles Wellford, 1871-1928 (Box C8)
  - Lee, Ivy Ledbetter, 1877-1934 (Box C8)
  - Lefferts, William (Box C8)
  - Lewis, Jane Perry Hone (Mrs. Charles Edward) (Box C8)
  - Lewis, William Eubene,-1924 (Box C8)
  - Limburg Stirum, Pieter Hendrik, Count van, 1792-1875 (Box C8)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 (Box C8)
  - Lippitt, Henry Frederick, 1856-1933 (Box C8)
  - Littlejohn, Abraham Newkirk, 1824-1901 (Box C8)
  - Livingston, Mortimer, 1807-1857 (Box C8)
  - Livingston, Silvia De Grasse De Pau (Mrs. Mortimer) (Box C8)
  - Livingston, Silvia Julia, 1833-1895 (Box C8)
  - Lorent, J. R. (Box C8)
  - Lorillard, Pierre, 1860-1940 (Box C8)
  - Loring, August us Peabody, 1856-1938 (Box C8)
  - Lüttgen, Walther (Box C8)
  - Lyman, Sylvanus R. (Box C8)
  - McAdoo, William Gibbs, 1863-1941 (Box C9)
  - McAllister, Ward, 1827-1895 (Box C9)
  - McAllister & Cohen (Savannah, GA) (Box C9)
  - McAneny, George, 1869-1953 (Box C9)
  - Macauley, Charles Raymond, 1871-1934 (Box C9)
  - McClellan, George Brinton, 1826-1885 (Box C9)
  - McClellan, George Brinton, 1865-1940 (Box C9)
  - McCook, John James, 1845-1911 (Box C9)
  - McCorkle, Joseph Walker, 1819-1885 (Box C9)
  - McCormick, Medill, 1877-1925 (Box C9)
  - Macdonald, Gordon, 1856-1908 (Box C9)
  - McHenry, Henry Davis, 1826-1890 (Box C9)
  - MacKay, Clarence Hungerford, 1874-1938 (Box C9)
  - Mackenzie, Catherine Alexander Robinson (Box C9)
  - (Mrs Alexander Slidell), I81U-I883 (Box C9)
  - Mackenzie, Harriet, 1844- (Box C9)
  - Mackenzie, Morris Robinson Slidell, 1848-1915 (Box C9)
  - McKibbin, Joseph Chambers, I824-I896 (Box C9)
  - McLean, Washington (Box C9)
  - McMillan, Emerson, 1844-1922 (Box C9)
  - Mann, William DfAlton, 1839-1920 (Box C9)
  - Marble, Manton Malone, 1835-1917 (Box C9)
  - Marchand, Raymonde de St Roman (Mrs. Jean Baptiste) (Box C9)
  - Marcosson, Isaac Frederick, 1877- (Box C9)
  - Marcy, William Learned, 1786-1857 (Box C9)
  - Martin, William R. (Box C9)
  - Mason, Charles, 1820-1894 (Box C9)
  - Mason, George Champlin, l820-l894 (Box C9)
  - Mason, George Champlin, Jr. (Box C9)
  - Mather, Samuel, 1851-1931 (Box C9)
  - Merrell, Lawrence (Box C9)
  - Merrell, Sarah Lawrence Perry (Mrs. Frederick W.) (Box C9)
  - Metcalf, Victor Howard, 1853-1936 (Box C9)
  - Metcalfe, James Stetson, 1858-1927 (Box C9)
  - Meyer, (Sir) Carl Ferdinand, 1851-1922 (Box C9)
  - Miller, George Maccolloch, 1832-1917 (Box C9)
  - Mills, Darius Ogden, 1825-1910 (Box C9)
  - Mills, John G. (Box C9)
  - Millson, John Singleton, 1808-1874 (Box C9)
  - Minot, Josiah (Box C9)
  - Mitchel, James (Box C9)
  - Mitchel, John Purroy, 1879-1918 (Box C9)
  - Mitchell, Silas Weir, 1829-1914 (Box C9)
  - Monaghan, James Charles, 1857-1917 (Box C9)
  - Morgan, Edwin D. (Box C9)
  - Morgan, L. L. (Box C9)
  - Morse, E. Rollins (Box C9)
  - Mortimer, Richard (Box C9)
  - Munn, Charles Allen,-1924 (Box C9)
  - Munroe, Henry W. (Box C9)
  - Munsey, Frank Andrew, 1854-1925 (Box C9)
  - Muser, W. Newton (Box C9)
  - Myers, Theodore Walter, 1844-1918 (Box C9)
  - Neilson, Louis (Box C9)
  - Nelson, George Francis, 1842-1932 (Box C9)
  - Niblack, William Ellis, 1822-1893 (Box C9)
  - Nicholson, John Anthony, 1827-1906 (Box C9)
  - Nilsson, Christine, 1843-1921 (Box C9)
  - Nordhoff, Charles, 1830-1901 (Box C9)
  - O'Brien, Morgan Joseph, 1852-1937 (Box C9)
  - O'Connor, James (Box C9)
  - O'Conor, Charles, 1804-1884 (Box C9)
  - Oelrichs, Charles May (Box C9)
  - Oelrichs, Hermann, 1850-1906 (Box C9)
  - Ogden, Annie (Box C9)
  - Olcott, Frederic P., 1850-1906 (Box C9)
  - Olcott, Jacob Van Vechten, 1856-1940 (Box C9)
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935 (Box C9)
  - Oudiné, Eugéne André, 1810-1887 (Box C9)
  - Paget, Mary L. G. St John Stevens, Lady,-1919 (Box C)
  - Parker, Amasa Junius, 1807-1890 (Box C)
  - Parker, James Henry, 1843-1915 (Box C)
  - Parson's, Elsie Worthington Clews (Mrs Herbert), 1875-1941 (Box C)
  - Parsons, Schuyler Livingston, 1852- (Box C)
  - Parsons, William Barclay, 1859-1932 (Box C)
  - Paul, George H. (Box C)
  - Peck, William E. (Box C)
  - Peel, (Lady) Emily Hay,-1924 (Box C)
  - Pendleton, Francis Key,-1930 (Box C)
  - Pepper, George Wharton, 1867- (Box C)
  - Perkins, Thomas Nelson, 1870-1937 (Box C)
  - Perry, Calbraith Bourne (Box C)
  - Perry, Matthew Calbraith, 1794-I858 (Box C)
  - Perry, Thomas Sergeant, 1845-1928 (Box C)
  - Peters, Georgina Snelling (Mrs. John C.) (Box C)
  - Peters, John Charles, 1819-1893 (Box C)
  - Peters, Ralph, 1853-1923 (Box C)
  - Pfyffer Heydegg, Caroline Slidell, Baroness von (Box C)
  - Phillips, Frederick J. (Box C)
  - Pierce, Franklin, 1853-1923 (& cataloged documents) (Box C)
  - Pinchot, Cornelia Elizabeth Bryce (Mrs. Gifford) (Box C)
  - Poniatowski, (Prince) Charles, 1897- (Box C)
  - Porter, Fitz-John, 1822-1901 (Box C)
  - Post, Edwin A. (Box C)
  - Potter, Henry Codman, 1834-1908 (Box C)
  - Powel, Samuel (Box C)
  - Prince, Frederick O. (Box C)
  - Pryor, Roger Atkinson, 1828-1919 (Box C)
  - Pulitzer, Ralph, 1879-1939 (Box C)
  - Purdy, August Belmont (Box C)
  - Purdy, John F. (Box C)
  - Randall, Samuel Jackson, 1828-1890 (Box C)
  - Randolph, Carman Fitz, 1856- (Box C)
  - Randolph, Theodore Fitz, 1826-1883 (Box C)
  - Ransom, Mathew Whitaker, 1826-1904 (Box C)
  - Rechteren van Ahnem, Elisa Martha van Limburg Stirum, Countess, 1803-1890 (Box C)
  - Redfield, William C., 1858-1932 (Box C)
  - Redmond, Mary L. (Box C)
  - Reed, James Alexander, 1861-1944 (Box C)
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1837-1912 (Box C)
  - Rice, Isaac Leopold, 1850-1915 (Box C)
  - Ridder, Herman, 1851-1915 (Box C)
  - Rives, Sara Swan Whiting Belmont (Mrs. George L.) (Box C)
  - Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt (Mrs. Douglas), 1861-1933 (Box C)
  - Robinson, Douglas, Jr. (Box C)
  - Robinson, Helen Rebecca Roosevelt (Mrs. Theodore) (Box C)
  - Rodgers, Alexander (Box C)
  - Rodgers, Christopher Raymond Perry, 1819-1892 (Box C)
  - Rodgers, Frederick, 1842-1917 (Box C)
  - Rodgers, Julia Slidell (Mrs. Christopher Raymond Perry) (Box C)
  - Rodgers, Raymond Perry, 1849-1925 (Box C)
  - Rodgers, Robert Smith (Box C)
  - Rokeby, Henry Robinson-Montagu, 6th Baron, 1798-1883 (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt (Mrs. Franklin D.) 1881-1962 (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Elliott, 1859-1894 (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Grace S. Lockwood (Mrs Archibald B.) (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Laura d’Orémieulx (Mrs. J. West) (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Philip James, 1892- (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Samuel Montgomery, 1864-1920 (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919 (Box C)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944 (Box C)
  - Root, Elihu, 1845-1937 (Box C)
  - Rosebery, Archibald Philip Primrose, 5th Earl of, 1847-1929 (Box C)
  - Rosebery, Hannah de Rothschild Primrose, Countess of, 1851-1890 (Box C)
  - Ross, Patrick Hore Warriner, 1858-1928 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Adelheid von Rothschild (Baroness Edmond de), 1853-1935 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Adolph von, 1823-1900 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Alfred Charles de, 1842-1918 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Alphonse de, 1827-1905 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Anthony Gustave, 1887-1961 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Arthur de, 1851-1903 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Betty von Rothschild (Baroness James de), 1805-1886 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Charlotte von Rothschild (Mrs. Lionel de), 1819-1884 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Edmond James de, 1845-1934 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Edouard Alphonse James de, 1868-1949 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Ferdinand James von, l839-1898 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Germaine Alice Halphen (Baroness Edouard de), 1884- (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) James Armand de, 1878-1957 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) James May er de, 1792-1868 (Box C)